<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Introduction</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview of plugin dbpage">
            <subsection name="Introduction">
                <p>
                The dbpage plugin allows to create online reports by extracting data from any database and presenting it 
                with the help of simple HTML templates.
                </p> 
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="Prerequisites">
                <p>
                In order to follow this tutorial, a knowledge of SQL and HTML is needed.
                </p> 
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section name="Overview of plugin dbpage">
            <subsection name="Choose your datasource(s)">
                <p>
                The datasource is declared as a pool in the <code>db.properties</code>.The datasource may be any database accessible by JDBC
                (i.e MySQL,PostgreSQL,Oracle,Microsoft SQL Server etc ...). The code snippet below shows how a pool may be declared 
                </p>

                <p>
                <pre>
#mypool.poolservice is not a mandatory property
mypool.poolservice=fr.paris.lutece.util.pool.service.LuteceConnectionService
mypool.driver=org.gjt.mm.mysql.Driver
mypool.url=jdbc:mysql://localhost/mydatabase?autoReconnect=true&amp;useUnicode=yes&amp;characterEncoding=utf8
mypool.user=
mypool.password=
mypool.initconns=2
mypool.maxconns=5
mypool.logintimeout=2000
mypool.checkvalidconnectionsql=SELECT 1
                </pre>              
                </p> 
                  <p>
                  Each section can be branched to a different or same pool as shown on the diagram below. The DbPage is composed of all the sections as
                  follows. This allows data synthesis by combination of many sections.
                <center>
                	<img
						src="images/dbpage_manual_002.gif"
						alt="Image" />
                </center>
      
                </p> 
            </subsection>

              <subsection name="Choose parameters to target the appropriate data">
                <p>
                The variables of a report may be a date, a project or any data. The choice of these parameters as variables in order to allow the
                user to scroll through the report depends on your user requirements.
                Please consult the usage section to see a simple usage
                of dbpage in a concrete example
                (e.g MyHelloWorld Report).
                </p> 
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Create the templates or use provided templates for rendering">
                <p>
                Each DbPage has a title and sections. The sections are of type form,table and selects. The choice of a template depends on the
                dataset that is collected by the sql query. Any esthetic concerns will be expressed into the template(colors,styles,size). The DbPage can be declared 
                directly in the Back Office or as text files that are uploaded on the server.This issue is treated in more details in the Usage section.
                </p>
                <p>
                <center>
                	<img
						src="images/dbpage_manual_001.gif"
						alt="Image" />
                </center>
      
                </p> 
                
            </subsection>
            
        </section>
        <section name="Publish in a few clicks">
          <p>
          The dbpage can be published as a portlet so that it can marry completely the general design of the Lutece CMS or as an XPage which will
          be accessed by a specific Url. In general a combination of the two can be used in order to handle form submission to enhance interaction
          while navigation through the data.  
          
          </p>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>